The tide is turning.
Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom is a action, adventure,
fantasy film directed by James Wan.
Black Manta seeks revenge on Aquaman for his father's death.
Wielding the Black Trident's power, he becomes a formidable foe.
To defend Atlantis, Arthur (Aquaman) forges an
alliance with his imprisoned brother.
They must protect the kingdom.
Arthur, played by Jason Momoa.
Orm, played by Patrick Wilson.
Black Manta, played by Yahya Abdul-Mateen II.
Dr. Shin, played by Randall Park.
Mera, played by Amber Heard.
Atlanna, played by Nicole Kidman.
Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom is a 2023 American superhero
film based on the DC Comics character Aquaman.
Directed by James Wan from a screenplay by David Leslie Johnson-McGoldrick, it is the sequel to
Aquaman (2018) and the 15th and final film in the DC Extended Universe (DCEU).
Jason Momoa stars as Arthur Curry / Aquaman, who must work with his half-brother Orm (Patrick Wilson) to prevent Black Manta (Yahya Abdul-Mateen II)
from killing his family and using the cursed Black Trident to overheat the world while searching for the lost seventh kingdom of the seas.
Amber Heard, Randall Park, Dolph Lundgren, Temuera Morrison, Martin
Short, and Nicole Kidman also star in supporting roles.
Momoa pitched a story for an Aquaman sequel during the first film's production.
Wan did not want to rush a sequel after the first film's commercial
success but agreed in January 2019 to oversee development.
Johnson-McGoldrick signed on to return as screenwriter a month later, and
Wan was confirmed to be returning as director in August 2020.
He said the film would expand on Aquaman's worldbuilding, have a more
serious tone, and feature themes such as climate change.
It is a buddy comedy between Aquaman and Orm, and was inspired by the Silver Age of Comic Books with a retro science fiction vibe similar
to the works of animator Ray Harryhausen and the horror films of the 1960s, specifically Planet of the Vampires (1965).
Wan announced the sequel's title in June 2021, and principal photography
began later that month and concluded in January 2022.
Filming took place in the United Kingdom, Hawaii, Los Angeles, and
New Jersey, with additional filming in New Zealand.
Several reshoots took place between July 2022 and June 2023 to alter the storyline while some actors' roles were
reduced, including Heard's, whose involvement was the subject of controversy during production.
Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom premiered at a fan event at the Grove, Los Angeles on
December 19, 2023, and was released in the United States on December 22.
The film received negative reviews from critics and grossed $440 million
worldwide against a production budget of $205–215 million.
The film explores themes of superhero, secret
society, half-brother, sequel, revenge.
The tone is lighthearted.